Guide to the Sula Benet Papers RISM.RG.2
New York University Archives
- Series II: Professional Papers
  - Subseries F: Longevity Studies Done By Others
    - Medical, undated (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Marriage-U.S.A., undated (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Project N.Y, Demography, undated (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Demography New York State, undated (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Health-USA, undated (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - 1970 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - 1970-1972 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - 1976 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - 1977, undated (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - 1979, undated (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - Publications and Essays, 1960s-1980s (Box 21, Folder 1-8)
    - Completed Work, circa 1980s (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Subseries G: Benet's U.S. Aging and Longevity Studies
    - Subsubseries II: New York Department of Aging
      - Population statistics (national, USA), undated (Box 25, Folder 1-10)
      - Oversized Graphs and Charts: 1970 Census, Age Distribution Charts (IA, FL, TX, SD, USA), undated (Box 26)
  - Subseries H: Benet's U.S./USSR Aging and Longevity Studies
    - Grants and Proposals: Misc. Aging Studies, 1976-1979 (Box 27, Folder 1-10)
    - Research Proposal, circa 1980s (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Grants, 1970-1971 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Applications, 1970s (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Drafts, 1970s (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Proposed Ethnography, 1977 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Div of Work Tasks, circa 1970s (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Ethnograph Statement/Goals, circa 1970s (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Medical Procedure, 1960 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Life Satisfaction Survey, 1978 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Life Satisfaction Paper, circa 1970s (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Coding/Questionnaires, circa 1970s (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Charts, circa 1970s (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Barrow Genealogical Data, undated (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Questionnaire, circa 1970s (Box 28, Folder 14-17)
    - Food Diary, undated (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - Notes on the Abkhasians, undated (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - Genealogical Forms/Polish?, undated (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - Notes, undated (Box 28, Folder 21)
    - Intro: US/USSR Aging Study, undated (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Mss.: US/USSR Aging Study, undated (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Kinship and Historical Research: Caucasus, undated (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Family/Genealogy Charts/Notes, undated (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Appendix, undated (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Diet (research for diet chapter), undated (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Short Biographies, undated (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Long-Living People-Profiles and Interviews, undated (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Profiles of long-living people, undated (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Profiles of long-living people, undated (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Language (Caucasus), undated (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Longevity and Reproduction, undated (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Land People of the Caucasus, undated (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Mss: Jews of Iran, undated (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Mss.: Islam, undated (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - Sula Benet articles, published and unpublished., 1970s (Box 30, Folder 1-27)
    - Misc. news articles re: aging and Benet's research in Caucasus, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Publication requests and correspondence, 1980s (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Letters re: publication, 1976 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Letters re: publication, 1980s (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Research Materials including a tape (folk songs), undated (Box 31, Folder 5A)
    - Kvitsinia Reviewed, undated (Box 31, Folder 5B)
    - Korkushko, et al Reviewed, 1985 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Mankovsky, et al Reviewed, 1983 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Miklashevskaya, et al Reviewed, 1982 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Pavlosky, Volkov-Dubrovin & Arkhangelskaya Reviewed, 1982 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Salamatina, et al Report 2 Reviewed, undated (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Salamatina, et al Reviewed, undated (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Smirnova & Shagurina Reviewed, 1982 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Reviewed (Starovoitova research), undated (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Tokar Reviewed, 1985 (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Voronov, et al Reviewed, undated (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Photographs, Oversized, undated (Box 32)
    - Photographs, Oversized: Misc landscapes and portraits (Georgia) and Shaman-Mexico polaroids and tape, undated (Box 33)
  - Subseries I: Audiovisual Materials, Benet, Sula, 1903-1982 (Box 34)
    Ethnology.; Aging -- United States.; Family.; Aging -- Latin America.; First drafts.; Older people |z Jamaica.; Ethnic groups.; Books.; Educational sociology.; Aging |z Russian S.F.S.R.; Education, Higher -- United States.; Education -- Study and teaching -- United States
    - U-Matic 60 Minutes "How to Live to be 100" air date 7/5/1981, 1981 July 5; cuid3 (Box Shared University Archives 140, U-matic cuid3)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      Duration: 17 Minutes
    - Audio cassette labeled on side 1: VNS side 2: Sula Benet WOR 7/21/1976, 1976 July 21; cuid4 (Box Shared University Archives 098)
    - Box of slides labeled "Hunza", undated; cuid5 (Box 34)
    - Audio cassette labeled 2 sides: Sula Benet, The MacCann show June 1976, 1976 June; cuid6 (Box Shared University Archives 098)
    - Audio cassette labeled "82-AAAS 30 Aging from Birth to Death, Part 1, Jan 3-8, 1982, Washington, D.C.", cuid332 (Box Shared University Archives 098)
      General
      "Aging from Birth to death: Biosocial Perspectives" Part 1 Presentations by: Gerald E. McClean, James F. Fries, J. Allan Herd, Richard Suzman, Judith Rodin
    - Audio cassette labeled "82-AAAS 31 Aging from Birth to Death, Part 2, Jan 3-8, 1982, Washington, D.C.", cuid7 (Box Shared University Archives 098, Cassette data_value_missing_79c3b78379913f3b5e14d19e67bd8583)
      General Note
      "Aging from Birth to death: Biosocial Perspectives" Part 2 Presentations by: Gerald E. McClean, James F. Fries, J. Allan Herd, Richard Suzman, Judith Rodin
    - Envelope of slides labeled "Hunza", undated; cuid8 (Box 34)
    - Small box of slides labeled "Hasan", undated; cuid9 (Box 34, Box-folder data_value_missing_6f9bfa76f8ac0cc5405245745ab624d4)
  - Subseries J: Oversized Materials: matted photos and newspapers (Abkhasia), 1960s (Box 35)
  - Subseries K: Book Collection
    - Book Collection with List of Titles from Bobcat (by Sula Benet and others), 1940s-1980s (Box 36)
    - Book Collection, 1940s-1980s (Box 37)
  - Subseries L: Unorganized Papers and Articles
    - Russia, undated (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Abkhasia, undated (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Family, undated (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Children, 1970s-1980s (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Genetics, 1970s (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Food-KY and Kieu, 1970s (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Bibliography, undated (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Research, 1940s-1970s (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Sadomskaia, Natasha (articles), 1966 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Theory (misc. articles), 1940s-1960s (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Folklore, undated (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Baltimore Longitudinal Study (US Public Health Service), undated (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Sula Benet Family Health article, undated (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Vilcabamba (news clippings), 1976 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Report Sachuk-Cheboterev, undated (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Why they live to be 100 or more, 1972 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Longevity, 1970s (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Maps, undated (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - "Report on my trip to the Soviet Union", 1974 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Sibecia-Old People, undated (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - Slaves, undated (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - Slave Gerontology, undated (Box 39, Folder 14)
    - Toasting, undated (Box 39, Folder 15)
    - Virtues of men and women, undated (Box 39, Folder 16)
    - Middle East, 1968 (Box 39, Folder 17)
    - Music, 1973 (Box 39, Folder 18)
    - Old Age, undated (Box 39, Folder 19)
    - Sex, 1970 (Box 39, Folder 20)
    - Walter C. McKain: "Visit to a Russian Village" and "Impressions of the Soviet Union", 1972 (Box 39, Folder 21)
    - Proverbs, undated (Box 39, Folder 22)
    - Working Paper-Longevity Proposal, 1977 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Research Outline, 1979 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Consultants, 1977 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Dr. Francis Lees, 1980 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Directory of Research, 1976 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Blood Analysis, circa 1970s (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Anthropometry, 1979 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Linear Measurements, undated (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - US Study (Demographics), 1970s (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - New Items re RISM/Soviet Project, 1977 (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - USA-USSR Longevity Project (Michael, Henry), 1976-1977 (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - U.S. Census and References, 1970s (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - Demographic Sources, 1976 (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - US/USSR Aging Preliminary Notes/Research Outline, circa 1977 (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - Longevity Working Draft, circa 1977 (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - Nutrition Carol Bryant, 1979 (Box 40, Folder 16)
    - Anti-Sera to Soviet Union, 1980 May 17 (Box 40, Folder 17)
    - Nutrition Christine Wilson, 1979 (Box 40, Folder 18)
    - Nutrition and Diet, 1977-1983 (Box 40, Folder 19)
    - Misc. Social Sciences Journals, articles, and meeting minutes, 1940s-1980s (Box 41)
    - Books and Publications re: longevity, demography, aging, and nutrition, 1940s-1980s (Box 42)
    - Journals, conference papers, newsletters, and articles, 1940s - 1970s (Box 43)
    - Conference lectures and articles re: aging, Eastern European ethnicity, and misc. publications, 1950s-1980s (Box 44)